A Guide to the Speeches of Governor Charles S. Robb, 1982-1984
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Speeches of Governor Charles S. Robb, 1982-1984
The Library of Virginia
51882
XX cubic foot (X boxes)
Office of the Governor
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Charles S. Sydnor, August 8, 2016. Accessioned August 8, 2016.
Biographical Information
Charles Spittal "Chuck" Robb was born June 26, 1939 in Phoenix, AZ, but grew up in Alexandria, VA. He is the son of Francis Howard Wooley and James Spittal Robb. He graduated from the University of Wisconsin-Madison in 1961 and joined the United States Marine Corps, graduating with honors from the Marine Corps training school in Quantico, VA. He worked as an aide at the White House and served two tours of duty during the Vietnam War. He graduated from the University of Virginia Law School in 1973, and clerked for a federal judge in the Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals before entering private practice in Northern Virginia. He served as Democratic Lieutenant Governor of Virginia (1978-1982), Governor of Virginia ( 1982-1986) and in the United States Senate (1989-2001). Following his two terms in the Senate, Robb joined the faculty at George Mason School of Law. He is married to Lynda Byrd Johnson Robb, daughter of former President Lyndon B. Johnson, and they have three daughters.
Charles W. Sydnor, Jr. served as Executive Assistant and Speechwriter for Governor Robb from 1982-1984. He was born in 1943 in Jefferson City, TN and received his B.A. in History from Emory and Henry (1965) and his M.A. (1967) and Doctorate (1971) from Vanderbilt University. Prior to joining the staff of Governor Robb, Syndor was a Professor at Longwood University (1972-1980) and Assistant to the President of Hampden-Sydney (1980-1982). After leaving state service, he served as President of the Emory and Henry (1984-1992), President of Commonwealth Public Broadcasting/Community Idea Stations (1992-2006), and Executive Director/Senior Historian with the Virginia Holocaust Museum (2013-). He is married to Linda Edwards and has four children.
Scope and Content
Speeches, 1982-1984, are housed in XX boxes and document the development of speeches for Governor Charles S. Robb. These particular files were created and maintained by Charles W. Sydnor, Jr., Executive Assistant and Speechewriter for Governor Robb. Records include finalized speeches, speech drafts and talking points, and may also include correspondence and memoranda related to the event, rough notes, and backbround information including articles, news clippings, reports, and event programs and intineraries. Some event folders may lack the finalized version of the speech.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in chronological order by event date.
Contents List
- Series I. Speeches, 1982-1984.
  - Inaugural Address, 1982 Jan 16. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly Address, 1982 Jan 18. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New Federalism Address, 1982 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - State Higher Education Executive Officers, 1982 Mar 25. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam War Memorial dedication, 1982 Mar 25. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - West Point Founder's Day, 1982 Apr 3. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - George Mason University Council of Visitors, 1982 Apr 5. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Governor's Dinner (South Carolina), 1982 Apr 6. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agency Head Luncheon, 1982 May 3. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Commencement Address - Norfolk State University (NSU), 1982 May 6. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Law Day - University of Virginia (UVA), 1982 May 7. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commencement Address - University of Virginia (UVA), 1982 May 9. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - University of Virginia (UVA) Alumni International Club, 1982 May 12. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hampton Roads Maritime Association - Annual banquet, 1982 May 13. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - World Trade Week - Luncheon, 1982 May 17. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Commencement Address - Virginia Military Institute (VMI), 1982 May. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agency Head briefing, 1982 June 9. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Naturalization Ceremony at Monticello, 1982 July 5. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carter O. Lowrance portrait ceremony, 1982 July 19. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rectors and Presidents of Virginia's Colleges, Universities and Community Colleges, 1982 July 17. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Association of State Budget Officers, 1982 July 28. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Urban League Convention, 1982 Aug 3. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Tractor Company, 1982 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local Government Officials Conference, 1982 Aug 16. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - International Coal Market, 1982 Aug 19. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Norfolk Ford Assembly Plant, 1982 Aug 25. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AFL-CIO, 1982 Aug 26. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tidewater Area Business and Contractor Association, 1982 Aug 27. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Development Advisory Board, 1982 Sept 1. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Science and Technology Task Force, 1982 Sept 2. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fairfax Judicial Center - Dedication, 1982 Sept 11. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Patriotism Day, 1982 Sept 11. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Peninsula Economic Development Council, 1982 Sept 14. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - North Atlantic Ports Association, 1982 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Southeast U.S./Japan Association, 1982 Sept 16. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fairfax Chamber of Commerce - Luncheon, 1982 Sept 17. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1982 Sept 17. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Strayer College - Dedication of Arlington Campus, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Senate Finance and House Appropriations Committees - Joint meeting, 1982 Sept 20. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pedestrian Safety Awards - Luncheon, 1982 Sept 21. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harriman Evening, 1982 Sept 21. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Manufacturer's Association, 1982 Sept 24. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - State Fair - Luncheon, 1982 Sept 28. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Private Industry Council, 1982 Sept 29. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Industrial Development - Seminar, 1982 Sept 29. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - DNC Finance Council - Luncheon, 1982 Sept 30. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clinic in Richlands - Dedication, 1982 Oct 2. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A. L. Philpott Technical Center at Patrick Henry Community College - Ground breaking, 1982 Oct 3. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Governor's Conference on Small Business, 1982 Oct 4. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - National Conference of State Retail Associations, 1982 Oct 5. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Urban Forum, 1982 Oct 5. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Amoco Plant - Dedication, 1982 Oct 7. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Association of School Administrators and Virginia Association of School Boards, 1982 Oct 7. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Arundel Library - Dedication, 1982 Oct 7. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - University of Virginia (UVA) Board of Visitors - Lunch with new members, 1982 Oct 8. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Council for Advancement and Support of Education - Convocation, 1982 Oct 9. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Source Telecomputing - Dedication, 1982 Oct 12. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - National Association of School Board Executives - Convention, 1982 Oct 14. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tidewater Associated General Contractors and American Institute of Architects, 1982 Oct 19. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Conference on World Trade, 1982 Oct 20. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Orby L. Cantrell Student Union Building at Clinch Valley College - Dedication, 1982 Oct 21. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Black Pastor's Conference, 1982 Oct 21. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Southern Industrial Development Council, 1982 Oct 25. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - New York Travel Writers - Reception and Luncheon, 1982 Oct 26. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Petersburg Chamber of Commerce, 1982 Oct 27. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Building Products Executives Conference, 1982 Oct 28. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Association of Realtors - Annual awards banquet, 1982 Oct 29. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Electric Plant - Opening, 1982 Oct 31. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dogwood House - Opening, 1982 Oct 31. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Drunk Driving Task Force - Luncheon, 1982 Nov 5. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Productivity Conference, 1982 Nov 6. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Report to Top Management, 1982 Nov 9. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Governor's Commission on Virginia's Future, 1982 Nov 11. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Medical Society, 1982 Nov 11. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Remarks to Agency Heads, 1982 Nov 16. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Public-Private Roundtable on Economic Development and Employment, 1982 Nov 17. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dominion Terminal Associates Ceremony, 1982 Nov 17. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Tidewater 5 Percent Investment Club Luncheon, 1982 Nov 17. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - American Insurance Company's International Symposium on Alcohol and Driving, 1982 Nov 17. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Charles H. Consolvo Center at St. Mary's Infant Home School - Dedication, 1982 Nov 17. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Friedrich Ebert Foundation's 4th German-American Economic Conference, 1982 Nov 18. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Home Builder's Association of Virginia Mid-Winter Conference, 1982 Nov 19. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Highways and Transportation Conference, 1982 Nov 18. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Businessmen's Luncheon at the Commmonwealth Club - The State of the World, 1982 Nov 29. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Conference on Employment and Training, 1982 Dec 3. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Metropolitan Business League Annual Awards Banquet, 1982 Dec 10. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Colon Club Breakfast, 1982 Dec 17. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - List of speeches, 1982 Aug-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 22)